const quizQuestions5en = [{
    question:"When using MIG/MAG welding, the adjustment of the arc voltage has a direct effect on:",
    answers: ["arc length, width of the weld, depth of penetration;",
    "arc length, deposition rate, spatter;",
    "depth of penetration, current value, spatter;",
    "deposition rate, width of the weld, spatter."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of using mixtures containing inert and active gases (Ar+O2, Ar+CO2, Ar+ O2+CO2) over the use of pure CO2 in GMAW process (MIG/MAG welding) is:",
    answers: ["Less defective weld metal (fewer inner imperfections).",
    "Metallurgical treatment of the weld, to improve its mechanical properties.",
    "Reduced spatter generation.",
    "Higher deposition rates are possible (for the same current value)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of using mixtures containing inert and active gases (Ar+O2, Ar+CO2, Ar+ O2+CO2) over the use of pure CO2 in GMAW process (MIG/MAG welding) is:",
    answers: ["Less defective weld metal (fewer inner imperfections).",
    "Metallurgical treatment of the weld, to improve its mechanical properties.",
    "Higher deposition rates are possible (for the same current value).",
    "Possibility of producing smaller droplet metal transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What material cannot be cut by plasma cutting process?",
    answers: ["Aluminium.",
    "Copper.",
    "Plastic.",
    "Cladded sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The maximum number of times an electrode can be re-dried is limited because:",
    answers: ["Thermal cycles, which the coating undergoes during redrying, can compromise its integrity;",
    "During redrying the electrode coating loses alloying elements;",
    "Each thermal cycle provokes a certain change in the chemical composition of the electrode core metal;",
    "With each thermal cycle the coating becomes drier and absorbs moisture more intensively."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the specification of the rutilic electrode E-6013, the digit “1” means that it can be used ...",
    answers: ["in overhead and flat positions;",
    "in all positions;",
    "in flat and horizontal positions;",
    "in horizontal and vertical positions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What does the number “70” mean in the E-7018 basic electrode specification?",
    answers: ["Minimum value for the tensile strength of the weld metal deposited with this electrode.",
    "Maximum value for the tensile strength of the weld metal deposited with this electrode.",
    "This number indicates that this is a basic type electrode.",
    "This number indicates that this is a basic type electrode for carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The MIG/MAG welding with short-circuiting metal transfer is commonly used…",
    answers: ["for sheets with a thickness above 12 mm;",
    "for out-of-position welding;",
    "when metal spatter is highly undesirable;",
    "when high heat input is desirable."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The MIG/MAG welding with short-circuiting metal transfer is commonly used…",
    answers: ["for sheets with a thickness above 12 mm;",
    "when metal spatter is highly undesirable;",
    "for root passes when welding thick plates;",
    "when high heat input is desirable."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The MIG/MAG welding with short-circuiting metal transfer is commonly used…",
    answers: ["for sheets with a thickness above 12 mm;",
    "when metal spatter is highly undesirable;",
    "when high heat input is desirable;",
    "for welding thin sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The slag produced when welding with a coated electrode:",
    answers: ["accelerates the cooling rate of molten metal;",
    "increases the welding process stability;",
    "increases the deposition rate;",
    "improves the weld bead appearance."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The slag produced when welding with a coated electrode:",
    answers: ["accelerates the cooling rate of molten metal;",
    "increases the welding process stability;",
    "increases the deposition rate;",
    "protects the metal droplets during the metal transfer and the weld pool from atmospheric gases."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The slag produced when welding with a coated electrode:",
    answers: ["accelerates the cooling rate of molten metal;",
    "reduces the cooling rate of molten weld metal;",
    "increases the welding process stability;",
    "increases the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Downwards welding has an advantage when:",
    answers: ["deep penetration is desirable;",
    "shallow penetration is desirable;",
    "thick material is being welded;",
    "the convex face of the weld is desirable."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A correct way to regulate the pressure of the wire feeder rollers in MIG/MAG welding is:",
    answers: ["Set the maximum pressure value to ensure that there will be no slippage.",
    "Hold the wire between your fingers without too much pressure and gradually increase the pressure on the rollers until the wire slides naturally between your fingers.",
    "Adjust the pressure until the roller contacts the wire and then give two more turns.",
    "No tightening is required as it is done automatically on modern equipment."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following can cause tungsten electrode contamination?",
    answers: ["Using a very high current.",
    "Touching the weld pool with the electrode.",
    "Too low arc voltage.",
    "Using forehand (pushing) welding techniques."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following can cause tungsten electrode contamination?",
    answers: ["Using a very high current.",
    "Touching the electrode with the filler metal rod.",
    "Too low arc voltage.",
    "Using forehand (pushing) welding techniques."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When welding with basic type electrodes, the appropriate arc length:",
    answers: ["is as short as possible;",
    "is equal to one electrode diameter;",
    "is equal to two electrode diameters;",
    "depends on the thickness of the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When applying the surfacing, dilution is generally lower for:",
    answers: ["straight beads;",
    "weaving beads;",
    "beads deposited with the backhand (drag) technique;",
    "lower welding speeds."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When applying the surfacing, dilution is generally lower for:",
    answers: ["straight beads;",
    "negative electrode polarity;",
    "beads deposited with the backhand (drag) technique;",
    "lower welding speeds."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When applying the surfacing, dilution is generally lower for:",
    answers: ["straight beads;",
    "positive electrode polarity;",
    "beads deposited with the forehand (push) technique;",
    "lower welding speeds."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause a slag inclusion when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["Current is too high.",
    "The groove is too wide.",
    "The arc is too long.",
    "Slag removal wasn't done properly."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause a slag inclusion when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["Current is too high.",
    "The groove is too wide.",
    "The arc is too long.",
    "The groove is too narrow."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A green-coded tungsten electrode would be a good choice for ...",
    answers: ["DCEP polarity TIG/GTAW welding carbon steel.",
    "DCEP polarity TIG/GTAW welding aluminium.",
    "Alternating Current TIG/GTAW welding stainless steels.",
    "Alternating Current TIG/GTAW welding aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode is attached to the collet on a TIG torch by turning:",
    answers: ["Ceramic cup.",
    "Collet itself.",
    "Tungsten electrode.",
    "Back cup."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When welding with a coated electrode, a too long arc can cause:",
    answers: ["A fine droplet metal transfer.",
    "A deeper penetration.",
    "A poorly-formed weld bead.",
    "A narrow bead."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which finishing process is preferred for the tungsten electrode (GTAW/TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Chemical cleaning.",
    "Polishing.",
    "Grinding.",
    "Etching."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The recommended torch inclination angle for the GTAW process (TIG welding) is:",
    answers: ["70 degrees to 90 degrees from the horizontal plane.",
    "70 degrees to 90 degrees from the vertical plane.",
    "Less than 70 degrees from the horizontal plane.",
    "Greater than 30 degrees from the vertical plane."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause exaggerated spatter when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["A very long arc.",
    "Wrong direct current polarity.",
    "Incorrect manipulation of the electrode.",
    "Too high welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause exaggerated spatter when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["Arc blow.",
    "Wrong direct current polarity.",
    "Incorrect manipulation of the electrode.",
    "Too high welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause exaggerated spatter when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["Electrode coating eccentricity.",
    "Wrong direct current polarity.",
    "Incorrect manipulation of the electrode.",
    "Too high welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause exaggerated spatter when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["Bad quality electrode.",
    "Wrong direct current polarity.",
    "Incorrect manipulation of the electrode.",
    "Too high welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can cause exaggerated spatter when welding with coated electrodes?",
    answers: ["Excessively high current.",
    "No-load voltage is too high.",
    "Incorrect manipulation of the electrode.",
    "Too high welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The weld finishing in the MMA (SMAW) process depends on:",
    answers: ["characteristics of the electrode coating, but can be improved by the welder.",
    "characteristics of the electrode coating, but can be made worse by the welder.",
    "characteristics of the electrode coating, and can be neither improved nor worsened by the welder.",
    "power source type (Constant Current type offers better finishing than Constant Voltage one)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the voltage setting is changed to higher values in conventional MAG welding:",
    answers: ["the arc length will increase;",
    "the wire feed speed will decrease;",
    "the current will increase;",
    "the weld width will decrease."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using MIG/MAG welding, the adjustment of the arc voltage has a direct effect on:",
    answers: ["the arc length;",
    "the welding current;",
    "the electrode wire fusion rate;",
    "the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using MIG/MAG welding, the adjustment of the arc voltage has a direct effect on:",
    answers: ["the width of the weld;",
    "the welding current value;",
    "the electrode wire fusion rate;",
    "the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using MIG/MAG welding, the adjustment of the arc voltage has a direct effect on:",
    answers: ["the depth of penetration;",
    "the welding current value;",
    "the electrode wire fusion rate;",
    "the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using MIG/MAG welding, the increase of the travel speed causes:",
    answers: ["higher penetration and narrower weld;",
    "higher penetration and broader weld;",
    "lower penetration and narrower weld;",
    "lower penetration and broader weld."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the torches used in flame cutting (oxyfuel), it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["There are torches capable of being used both in cutting and in gas welding.",
    "The mixture of the acetylene with the oxygen is always done outside the torch, in a special chamber, before entering the torch body.",
    " On the market, one can find only nozzles with oval holes for directing the oxygen jet.",
    "They can be curved at 90º near the nozzle for manual cuts or be straight for coupling with automatic cutting machines."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following conduits (guides) is most suitable for use in the MIG/MAG or FCAW torch when using steel electrodes?",
    answers: ["PVC graphite conduit.",
    "Teflon conduit.",
    "Steel spiral conduit.",
    "Rubber conduit with steel reinforcement."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What would you do to avoid using the wrong coated electrode?",
    answers: ["I would choose the same electrode I have already used for a similar weld.",
    "I would choose the electrode indicated by an experienced welder.",
    "I would check whether the designation of the electrode to be used complies with the welding procedure specification.",
    "I would check whether the electrode length complies with the welding procedure specification."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"You would choose the diameter of the coated electrode to be used for a given joint based on:",
    answers: ["the electrode manufacturer's catalogue;",
    "the thickness of the base metal;",
    "the required weld length;",
    "the time available to fulfil the welding (the larger diameter, the less time spent)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Higher welding speeds can be achieved:",
    answers: ["with upwards progression;",
    "with downwards progression;",
    "with upwards progression and with weaving.",
    "with weaving in flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What type of electrode (as to its coating) is most commonly used for the vertical downward position?",
    answers: ["Rutile type (e.g., E6013).",
    "Basic type (e.g., E7018).",
    "Acid type (e.g., E7020).",
    "Cellulosic type (e.g., E6010)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What should be the distance between the workpiece and the contact tip in MIG/MAG welding of carbon steel with a short arc and a 1.0 mm diameter electrode?",
    answers: ["Between 25 and 30 mm, depending on the current value.",
    "Between 10 and 15 mm.",
    "As short as possible, as long as the contact tip does not touch the weld pool.",
    "Approximately 20 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In what emergency does the safety valve, installed on the pressure regulator, allow the gas to escape (oxy-gas welding/cutting)?",
    answers: ["Excessive heat (too high pressure)",
    "Low pressure (gas running out).",
    "Gas flow is too high.",
    "When there is necessary to maintain the same work pressure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In what sequence should you open the valves for acetylene gas cutting?",
    answers: ["First the oxygen valve, then the acetylene valve and finally the ignition.",
    "First the acetylene valve, then the oxygen valve and finally the ignition.",
    "First the acetylene valve, then carry out the ignition, and finally open the oxygen valve.",
    "First the oxygen valve, then carry out the ignition and finally open the acetylene valve."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When does a short arc (short circuit transfer) facilitate MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Only in the flat position, especially for thick parts.",
    "Only in flat and horizontal position.",
    "In all positions and for root passes in butt joints.",
    "Only in vertical downward position."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are only few types of material that can be welded.",
    "Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base metal.",
    "Not suitable in field conditions with even slow winds.",
    "Porosity is difficult to be avoided."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base metal.",
    "It is difficult to avoid lack of fusion at the weld root.",
    "Lower welding speed than many other arc welding processes.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base metal.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Low filler metal deposition rates.",
    "Porosity is difficult to be avoided."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are only few types of material that can be welded.",
    "It is difficult to avoid lack of fusion at the weld root.",
    "Good hand-eye coordination is a necessary skill.",
    "Porosity is difficult to be avoided."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are only few types of material that can be welded.",
    "It is difficult to avoid lack of fusion at the weld root.",
    "It requires a high level of skill and dexterity when compared to other welding processes.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base metal.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Displays an open arc. Proper care must be taken to protect the welder and bystanders from harmful UV rays.",
    "Porosity is difficult to be avoided."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base metal.",
    "The used shielding gases are expensive.",
    "Porosity is difficult to be avoided."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are very limited types of material that can be welded.",
    "The lack fusion (cold lap) is difficult to be avoided.",
    "There is a risk of tungsten inclusions in the weld.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It does not allow to deposit filler metal in the overhead position.",
    "High gas flow rates are required.",
    "Low filler metal deposition rate.",
    "Constant Current type power sources are required."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Equipment costs can be lower than with many other welding processes.",
    "Fewer fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Higher filler metal deposition rate than many other welding processes.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Equipment costs can be lower than with many other welding processes.",
    "Especially good for welding thin sections and delicate parts.",
    "Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "It can be used as an autogenous process (without addition of filler metal).",
    "Equipment costs can be lower than with many other welding processes.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "Unlike SMAW (MMA) or GMAW (MIG/MAG), this process does not require a consumable filler metal for each application.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "No slag to obscure the welder's view of the weld pool.",
    "It is very suitable in extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "Higher filler metal deposition rate than many other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["If you increase the wire feed speed, the current increases proportionally.",
    "If you increase the wire feed speed, the current increases proportionately, while the arc voltage rises only a little.",
    "If you increase the no-load voltage of the power source, the arc voltage increases, while the current drops a little (due to the greater resistance of a longer arc).",
    "If the welding speed is increased, the arc voltage and welding current will drop slightly."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["If you increase the wire feed speed, the current increases proportionately, while the arc voltage rises only a little.",
    "If you increase the no-load voltage of the power source, the arc voltage increases, but the current remains almost constant.",
    "If you increase the no-load voltage of the power source, the arc voltage increases, while the current drops a little (due to the greater resistance of a longer arc).",
    "If the welding speed is increased, the arc voltage and welding current will drop slightly."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In manual TIG welding, the arc voltage depends on:",
    answers: ["the voltage adjustment on the control panel;",
    "the current value only;",
    "the electrode - workpiece distance;",
    "the electrode - workpiece distance and the current value."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Shielding gas cylinders for arc welding processes must never be completely emptied, as:",
    answers: ["the residual gas will be contaminated by dirt;",
    "the pressure inside the cylinder will become negative;",
    "it will be difficult to determine the type of gas to recharge;",
    "the cylinder will become contaminated with gas from the atmosphere."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"A long \"\"torch cap\"\" is used on GTAW (TIG Welding) torches to:\"",
    answers: ["prevent a shielding gas leak;",
    "control torch tilt (inclination).",
    "avoid accidental arcs.",
    "ensure good torch ergonomics."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What would you do if you need to reduce penetration in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["I would increase the welding speed.",
    "I would reduce the arc voltage.",
    "\"I would change the welding technique from \"\"pushing\"\" (forehand) to \"\"pulling\"\" (backhand).\"",
    "I would change the shielding gas to a CO2 rich mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What would you do if you need to reduce penetration in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["I would reduce the arc voltage.",
    "\"I would change the welding technique from \"\"pushing\"\" (forehand) to \"\"pulling\"\" (backhand).\"",
    "I would reduce the welding current and, accordingly, the arc voltage.",
    "I would change the shielding gas to a CO2 rich mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the FCAW process with the GMAW one, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["\"In the FCAW process, the bead profile is practically the same as that obtained by the solid wire process, with a \"\"finger\"\" (\"\"wine-glass\"\") shaped melting area.\"",
    "In the FCAW process it is recommended to use 4 rollers in the feeding system, while in the GMAW process in many cases just a pair of rollers is enough.",
    "The FCAW has a lower deposition rate (for the same current) as the central part of its section is occupied by a flux.",
    "The FCAW process cannot be used in the vertical position as the slag has a tendency to run down."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the FCAW process with the GMAW one, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["\"In the FCAW process, the bead profile is practically the same as that obtained by the solid wire process, with a \"\"finger\"\" (\"\"wine-glass\"\") shaped melting area.\"",
    "The FCAW has a lower deposition rate (for the same current) as the central part of its section is occupied by a flux.",
    "In both processes it is possible to use pure CO2 as a shielding gas.",
    "The FCAW process cannot be used in the vertical position as the slag has a tendency to run down."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the FCAW process with the GMAW one, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["\"In the FCAW process, the bead profile is practically the same as that obtained by the solid wire process, with a \"\"finger\"\" (\"\"wine-glass\"\") shaped melting area.\"",
    "The FCAW has a lower deposition rate (for the same current) as the central part of its section is occupied by a flux.",
    "The FCAW process cannot be used in the vertical position as the slag has a tendency to run down.",
    "FCAW favours a better weld finishing, as the formed slag helps to shape the profile of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The Ar+CO2 mixture is the most used mixture for welding carbon steel. About this mixture it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The higher the CO2 content in the mixture, the more suitable it becomes for welding thin sheets.",
    "It is mostly used for price reasons, although pure argon (very expensive) is the most suitable for welding carbon steel.",
    "The main purpose of adding CO2 is to reduce spattering.",
    "An important purpose of adding CO2 is to increase the heat input for the same current and welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The Ar+CO2 mixture is the most used mixture for welding carbon steel. About this mixture it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The higher the CO2 content in the mixture, the more suitable it becomes for welding thick plates.",
    "It is mostly used for price reasons, although pure argon (very expensive) is the most suitable for welding carbon steel.",
    "The main purpose of adding CO2 is to reduce spattering.",
    "An important purpose of adding CO2 is to improve the weld face finishing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When is it highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the semi-automatic MIG/MAG or FCAW welding feed system?",
    answers: ["When welding with flux cored wires (FCAW) of any diameter.",
    "When welding with solid wire with a diameter equal to or greater than 1.6 mm.",
    "When welding with spray transfer, as this type of metal transfer requires very high feed speeds.",
    "When welding in the overhead position, when the propulsion resistance of the wire inside the conduit (guide) is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When is it highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the semi-automatic MIG/MAG or FCAW welding feed system?",
    answers: ["When welding with solid wire with a diameter equal to or greater than 1.6 mm.",
    "When welding with aluminium wires of any diameter.",
    "When welding with spray transfer, as this type of metal transfer requires very high feed speeds.",
    "When welding in the overhead position, when the propulsion resistance of the wire inside the conduit (guide) is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When is it highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the semi-automatic MIG/MAG or FCAW welding feed system?",
    answers: ["When welding with solid wire with a diameter equal to or greater than 1.6 mm.",
    "When welding with spray transfer, as this type of metal transfer requires very high feed speeds.",
    "When welding with solid wire with a diameter smaller than 1.0 mm.",
    "When welding in the overhead position, when the propulsion resistance of the wire inside the conduit (guide) is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When is it highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the semi-automatic MIG/MAG or FCAW welding feed system?",
    answers: ["When welding with solid wire with a diameter equal to or greater than 1.6 mm.",
    "When the torch hose length is longer than 3 meters.",
    "When welding with spray transfer, as this type of metal transfer requires very high feed speeds.",
    "When welding in the overhead position, when the propulsion resistance of the wire inside the conduit (guide) is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements forms the protective oxide in stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Chromium.",
    "Nickel.",
    "Manganese.",
    "Molybdenum."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Rapid cooling of a steel from the austenitization temperature results in a rigid, brittle structure known as:",
    answers: ["ferrite;",
    "perlite;",
    "cementite;",
    "martensite."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Rapid cooling of a steel from the austenitization temperature results in a rigid, brittle structure known as:",
    answers: ["ledeburite;",
    "perlite;",
    "bainite;",
    "martensite."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"To ensure best weldability, characteristics, and minimize cracking, carbon should be kept below:",
    answers: ["0.20%.",
    "0.40%.",
    "0.60%.",
    "1.0%."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Prior to the welding operation, it is common to preheat the region, close to where the weld will be performed, at a specified temperature. Choose the reason for this:",
    answers: ["To dry them in order to avoid contamination of the weld by humidity (dew, rain, etc);",
    "Make the weld region warmer to provide a lower cooling speed and, thus, to avoid cold cracks;",
    "To reduce sheet deformation;",
    "To increase the melting rate of the base metal and thus to increase penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Stainless steel CANNOT be welded by:",
    answers: ["MMA welding;",
    "MIG/MAG welding;",
    "TIG welding;",
    "Oxyfuel gas welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of your friends asks you to weld a piece of carbon steel to a piece of aluminium with covered electrodes. Your answer should be like this:",
    answers: ["It is possible, but I will need electrodes for carbon steel of the basic type.",
    "It is possible, but I will need aluminium electrodes.",
    "It is possible, but I will need basic type carbon steel electrodes on the steel side and aluminium electrodes on the aluminium side.",
    "This is not possible."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which method will control the cooling rate of a weldment?",
    answers: ["Preheating.",
    "Altering backhand (dragging) and forehand (pushing) welding technique.",
    "Applying pulsed welding instead of short-circuit technique.",
    "Modifying the shielding gas mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which method will control the cooling rate of a weldment?",
    answers: ["Insulating with dry sand.",
    "Altering backhand (dragging) and forehand (pushing) welding technique.",
    "Applying pulsed welding instead of short-circuit technique.",
    "Modifying the shielding gas mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which method will control the cooling rate of a weldment?",
    answers: ["Maintaining correct interpass temperature.",
    "Altering backhand (dragging) and forehand (pushing) welding technique.",
    "Applying pulsed welding instead of short-circuit technique.",
    "Modifying the shielding gas mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which method will control the cooling rate of a weldment?",
    answers: ["Applying post heat.",
    "Altering backhand (dragging) and forehand (pushing) welding technique.",
    "Applying pulsed welding instead of short-circuit technique.",
    "Modifying the shielding gas mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Most non-ferrous metals ...",
    answers: ["show sparks of blue colour.",
    "show sparks of yellow colour.",
    "show sparks of red colour.",
    "will not show any sparks."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following welding practices with covered electrodes can result in cracks in the welds?",
    answers: ["Use of electrodes with a thick coating.",
    "Use of wet covered electrodes.",
    "Welding with rutilic electrodes with the Negative Electrode polarity (DCEN).",
    "Welding with rutilic electrodes with the Positive Electrode polarity (DCEP)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which property have austenitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["They have a high electrical conductivity.",
    "They have a high thermal conductivity.",
    "They have high corrosion resistance.",
    "They are suitable for flame cutting."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Before starting welding of stainless steels the following should be performed:",
    answers: ["the joint preparation shall be free from any contamination and cleaned;",
    "a preheating shall be always applied;",
    "the visible rust in the joint preparation shall be removed with a stainless steel brush;",
    "all tack welds shall be ground out."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which welding processes are suitable for welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["MMA(SMAW) and MAG welding.",
    "MMA(SMAW) and FCAW.",
    "MIG welding and TIG(GTAW).",
    "MAG welding and FCAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the most suitable shielding gas for MIG-welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["Argon.",
    "Gas mixture argon + oxygen.",
    "Gas mixture argon + CO2.",
    "CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The heat treatment most likely to reduce cracking in a weld is: ",
    answers: ["quenching;",
    "preheat;",
    "annealing;",
    "post heat."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When MIG/MAG welding steel a suitable gas flow rate for an electrode wire with a diameter of 1 mm is:",
    answers: ["4 l/min;",
    "6 l/min;",
    "10 l/min;",
    "15 l/min."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The heat input for stainless steels compared to non-alloy steels shall generally be:",
    answers: ["higher for ferritic stainless steels, but lower for martensitic ones;",
    "lower for all type of stainless steels;",
    "higher for austenitic stainless steels, but lower for martensitic ones;",
    "higher for austenitic and ferritic stainless steels, but lower for martensitic ones (to minimize the quenching)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Compared to non-alloy steels the sensitivity for distortion of stainless steels is:",
    answers: ["higher for ferritic stainless steels, but lower for martensitic ones;",
    "higher for all type of stainless steels;",
    "higher for austenitic stainless steels, but lower for martensitic ones;",
    "higher for austenitic and ferritic stainless steels, but lower for martensitic ones (due to the quenching phenomenon)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which backing gas should be used for MIG-welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["Argon.",
    "Gas mixture argon + oxygen.",
    "Gas mixture nitrogen + hydrogen.",
    "CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the identifying colours on the gas cylinder for argon and helium according to EN 1089-3?",
    answers: ["Argon: brown/white and- helium: green/red.",
    "Argon: white and helium: red.",
    "Argon: yellow/white and helium: blue.",
    "Argon: green and helium: brown."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Before starting welding the welder should check:",
    answers: ["welding consumables;",
    "weld penetration;",
    "WPS expiration date;",
    "the environment temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Before starting welding the welder should check:",
    answers: ["joint preparation;",
    "weld penetration;",
    "WPS expiration date;",
    "the environment temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Before starting welding the welder should check:",
    answers: ["pre-heating;",
    "weld penetration;",
    "WPS expiration date;",
    "the environment temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"If the thickness of the parent material decreases:",
    answers: ["the cooling rate does not change;",
    "the cooling rate increases;",
    "the cooling rate decreases too;",
    "there is no need for preheating"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"If the thickness of the parent material increases:",
    answers: ["the cooling rate does not change;",
    "the cooling rate decreases;",
    "the cooling rate increases too;",
    "the joint shall be preheated."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When is a steel weldable without pre-heating?",
    answers: ["When the carbon content is below 0.25%.",
    "When the carbon content is around 0.40%.",
    "When the carbon content is around 0.60%.",
    "When the carbon content is around 1.0% and lower."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The heat input in arc welding is calculated using the values of:",
    answers: ["welding current and no-load voltage;",
    "welding current, arc voltage and travel speed;",
    "welding current, preheat temperature and travel speed;",
    "welding current, interpass temperature and travel speed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The TIG welding with alternating current is suitable to weld:",
    answers: ["carbon steel;",
    "stainless steel;",
    "aluminium;",
    "copper."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which shielding gas is mostly used for the TIG-welding of non-alloy steel?",
    answers: ["Mixtures nitrogen + hydrogen.",
    "Pure argon or mixtures argon + helium.",
    "Mixtures argon + oxygen.",
    "Mixtures argon + hydrogen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which polarity do you choose for MIG welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["Direct Current Electrode Negative (DCEN).",
    "Direct Current Electrode Positive (DCEP).",
    "Alternating Current (AC).",
    "Pulsed Current (PC)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In TIG-welding the shielding gas is used: ",
    answers: ["primarily to protect the weld pool from the air;",
    "primarily to protect the weld pool from the air and also to alloy the weld metal;",
    "to alloy the weld metal and also to increase the heat input;",
    "to protect the tungsten electrode and the weld pool from the air."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which metal is more likely to crack due to weld joint shrinkage?",
    answers: ["Stainless steel.",
    "Copper.",
    "Cast iron.",
    "Carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When you have to choose covered electrodes for a new MMA welding (SMAW) work, you will use:",
    answers: ["the electrodes suggested by other welders;",
    "the electrodes you're accustomed to use;",
    "the electrodes indicated in the welding procedure specification (WPS), on the drawing or indicated by the welding co-ordinator;",
    "the best available electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When has a steel good weldability?",
    answers: ["When the carbon content is below 0.25%.",
    "When the carbon content is above 0.25%.",
    "When the carbon content is below 0.50%.",
    "When the steel has a high carbon and manganese."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the electrode inclination for downhill MMA welding (SMAW)? ",
    answers: ["perpendicular to 5 degrees;",
    "5 degrees to 15 degrees backhand (drag);",
    "15 degrees to 25 degrees backhand (drag);",
    "30 degrees to 45 degrees backhand (drag)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the electrode inclination for uphill MMA welding (SMAW)? ",
    answers: ["perpendicular to 5 degrees;",
    "5 degrees to 15 degrees forehand (push);",
    "15 degrees to 25 degrees forehand (push);",
    "30 degrees to 45 degrees forehand (push)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Current ranges for austenitic stainless steel covered electrodes are generally:",
    answers: ["10% to 15% lower than for the same size carbon steel electrodes;",
    "10% to 15% higher than for the same size carbon steel electrodes;",
    "about 20% higher than for the same size carbon steel electrodes;",
    "about the same as for carbon steel electrodes of the same size."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding stainless steel, good fabrication practice may include:",
    answers: ["using any tool (maid of bronze, high strength steel, aluminium, ...) as long as it is clean;",
    "using any tool (maid of bronze, high strength steel, aluminium, ...), provided it was always used for stainless steels only;",
    "using any tool (maid of bronze, high strength steel, aluminium, ...) as long as it is new;",
    "removing all moisture from the joint region before welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding stainless steel, good fabrication practice may include:",
    answers: ["using any tool (maid of bronze, high strength steel, aluminium, ...) as long as it is clean;",
    "using any tool (maid of bronze, high strength steel, aluminium, ...), provided it was always used for stainless steels only;",
    "using any tool (maid of bronze, high strength steel, aluminium, ...) as long as it is new;",
    "using aluminium oxide grinding discs."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following might cause lack of fusion in TIG welding?",
    answers: ["Too high shielding gas flow rate.",
    "Excessive electrode extension.",
    "Too long of an arc length.",
    "Too short of an arc length."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following will not affect the size of the heat affected zone (HAZ) of a weld: ",
    answers: ["Type of material.",
    "Heat input.",
    "Number of passes.",
    "Position of welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following gases can produce the highest flame temperature? ",
    answers: ["Propane.",
    "Acetylene.",
    "Natural gas.",
    "LPG."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The biggest problem during welding upon a painted surface is ...",
    answers: ["smoke;",
    "bad smell;",
    "porosity in the weld metal;",
    "bad weld appearance."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"What is the most critical area of a welded joint regarding stress concentration?",
    answers: ["The weld centre line.",
    "The weld toe.",
    "The back side of the weld.",
    "The weld start-stop points."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is a basic type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Butt joint.",
    "\"\"\"V\"\" joint.\"",
    "Root joint.",
    "Butt-to-Butt joint."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is a basic type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["\"\"\"V\"\" joint.\"",
    "Corner joint.",
    "Root joint.",
    "Butt-to-Butt joint."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is a basic type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Root joint.",
    "\"\"\"V\"\" joint.\"",
    "T-joint.",
    "Butt-to-Butt joint."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is a basic type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Butt-to-Butt joint.",
    "\"\"\"V\"\" joint.\"",
    "Root joint.",
    "Edge joint."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is a basic type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Root joint.",
    "\"\"\"V\"\" joint.\"",
    "Lap joint.",
    "Butt-to-Butt joint."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which joint preparation is best suited for welding thin sheets less than 3 mm thick?",
    answers: ["Double V.",
    "Single V.",
    "Square.",
    "Single U."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The “a” value of a fillet weld is:",
    answers: ["The height of a triangle inscribed in the weld cross section;",
    "The thickness of the thinnest plate of the welded joint;",
    "The length of the fillet weld leg;",
    "The cross-sectional area of the fillet weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The type of weld having a generally triangular cross section and which is applied to either a T-, corner, or lap joint is called the:",
    answers: ["butt weld;",
    "fillet weld;",
    "top weld;",
    "corner weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which joint preparation is the most appropriate for butt joints of pipes with diameters less than 200 mm and 10 mm wall thickness?",
    answers: ["Double V.",
    "Square.",
    "Double U.",
    "Single V."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the weld reinforcement (excess weld metal)?",
    answers: ["The weld surface opposite the weld root.",
    "Maximum height reached by excess filler material, measured from the surface of the base material.",
    "Maximum weld height, measured in the cross-sectional area occupied by the filler metal between the root and the face of the weld.",
    "Maximum weld height, measured in the cross-sectional area occupied by the filler metal between the root and the base metal surface."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The most convenient edge preparation in a butt joint with a thickness over 100 mm is:",
    answers: ["Single V.",
    "Double V.",
    "Square.",
    "Double U."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which condition should be avoided to reduce notch effect?",
    answers: ["Excessive weld convexity.",
    "Low heat input. ",
    "Excessive welding speed.",
    "Long arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the weld toe?",
    answers: ["Surface opposite the weld root.",
    "Weld surface opposite the face of the weld.",
    "Lateral geometric boundaries (side surface) of a weld.",
    "The line of the junction of the weld face and the base metal surface."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Minimum size of leg length of fillet weld for base metal plate of 10 mm thickness should be around:",
    answers: ["3 mm;",
    "5 mm;",
    "7 mm;",
    "9 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which precautions should be taken to minimise a fire risk during welding?",
    answers: ["Have a fire extinguisher in the vicinity.",
    "Have an observer to watch the working environment.",
    "Remove all inflammable objects or cover them with fire-proof blankets, have a fire hose or a fire extinguisher in the vicinity.",
    "Try to weld with as lower current as possible, reducing the heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Accessories using for SMAW/MMA welding process are:",
    answers: ["welding hammer for slag removing, wire brush, nozzle cleaner;",
    "welding hammer for slag removing, wire brush, spark lighter;",
    "welding hammer for slag removing, wire brush, nozzle flowmeter;",
    "welding hammer for slag removing, wire brush, electrode dryer."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the risks during slag removal and how to protect yourself?",
    answers: ["Hot slag parts can hit the eyes and the skin. Use your hand as shield for protection for the eyes.",
    "Hot slag parts can hit the eyes and the skin. Use safety glasses and wear protective clothing.",
    "Hot slag parts can hit the eyes and the skin. Wait until the slag cools down before removal.",
    "Hot slag cannot be removed because the weld would be subjected to oxidation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A problem that occurs in welds caused by non-uniform heating is:",
    answers: ["Porosity.",
    "Incomplete fusion.",
    "Distortion.",
    "Slag inclusions."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk of gas poisoning during welding depends mainly on:",
    answers: ["the type of base material;",
    "the type of welding process;",
    "the position of the welder's head;",
    "the filler metal type."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To avoid inhaling fumes while welding, the welder must:",
    answers: ["position his head properly;",
    "use the pulling (backhand) welding technique;",
    "use the pushing (forehand) welding technique;",
    "always weld with an airflow that carries the fumes outside."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the first thing to check before welding?",
    answers: ["All wiring and connections;",
    "Welding curtains;",
    "Whether the power source is working;",
    "Ventilation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What should you do if the ventilation is not working?",
    answers: ["Open all windows ensuring natural ventilation.",
    "Inform my supervisor before start to weld.",
    "Keep my head out of the smoke.",
    "Refuse to weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What should you do if the ventilation system is not working?",
    answers: ["Open all windows ensuring natural ventilation;",
    "Wear a respirator.",
    "Keep my head out of the smoke",
    "Refuse to work."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"How should the smoke extractor be positioned in a welding shop?",
    answers: ["Near the welding arc.",
    "Under the bench.",
    "On the roof of the shop.",
    "Behind the welder."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"An angular distortion would be higher in:",
    answers: ["a single V butt weld than in a single U butt weld.",
    "a double U butt weld than in a single U butt weld.",
    "a double V (X) butt weld than in a single V butt weld.",
    "a double U butt weld than a double V (V) butt weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Using a wet covered electrode can cause:",
    answers: ["internal undercut;",
    "porosity;",
    "excessive reinforcement;",
    "lack of penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the best protection against gases released by the welding process?",
    answers: ["Welding fume extractor.",
    "Protection mask.",
    "Proper position of the welder.",
    "Fan directed on the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why should you collect covered electrode stubs regularly?",
    answers: ["So, they can be recycled.",
    "The shop floor must be clean.",
    "They are a tripping hazard.",
    "Modern factories do not have cleaning women, who clean the environment are the workers themselves."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"When a workpiece is clamped to control distortion, the weld will always have:",
    answers: ["a brittle heat affected zone;",
    "high residual stress;",
    "high hardness;",
    "concavity (lack of filling)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Taking your safety glasses off is OK to do when:",
    answers: ["you have a welding helmet on;",
    "you are out of the range of sparks;",
    "you are out of the work area;",
    "all other safety devices are in place."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Taking your safety glasses off is OK to do when:",
    answers: ["you have a welding helmet on;",
    "you are out of the range of sparks;",
    "your work day is over;",
    "all other safety devices are in place."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Taking your safety glasses off is OK to do when:",
    answers: ["you are aware of the hazards and can react to them;",
    "you aren't doing anything;",
    "you are out of the shop;",
    "they get scratched."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"If you are asked to weld a tank that smells like gas, you should:",
    answers: ["use only MIG (not MAG) welding;",
    "throw a match in it from a distance to burn off vapours;",
    "purge it with oxygen;",
    "purge it with argon or carbon monoxide."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following welding practices with covered electrodes can result in cracks in the welds?",
    answers: ["Use of thick coating electrodes.",
    "Welding over paint or other impurities.",
    "Welding with rutile electrodes in electrode negative polarity (CCEN).",
    "Welding with rutile electrodes in electrode positive polarity (CCEP)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A depression, in the form of a notch, along the weld toe is?",
    answers: ["Incompletely filled groove.",
    "Undercut.",
    "Lack of fusion.",
    "Crater."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"How is called the discontinuity of the weld, when the welder does not completely fill the groove?",
    answers: ["Incompletely filled groove.",
    "Recess.",
    "Lack of fusion.",
    "Crater."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The weld discontinuity when there is too much of deposited weld metal is known as:",
    answers: ["Excess of convexity.",
    "Excess weld metal.",
    "Excessive fusion.",
    "Overlap."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The discontinuity that results from gas trapping within the weld metal is called:",
    answers: ["Crater pipe.",
    "Gas inclusion.",
    "Lack of fusion.",
    "Porosity."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To avoid the generation of weld defects, the welder must:",
    answers: ["adjust welding procedure specification (WPS) to actual welding conditions;",
    "strictly follow the WPS;",
    "Follow good practice tips from more experienced welders, modifying the WPS if necessary;",
    "choose the WPS that he thinks is the most suitable for the welding in question."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which safety component must be used in oxyacetylene welding/cutting equipment?",
    answers: ["Rotameter.",
    "Acetylene regulating valve.",
    "Flame arrester valve.",
    "Chain to hold cylinders."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding where the general public may be exposed to the rays of the arc, what should the welder do?",
    answers: ["Proper screens and warning signs.",
    "Rope off the area.",
    "Inform the safety coordinator.",
    "Give a verbal warning before starting to weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding Residual Stresses:",
    answers: ["Residual stresses are stresses that remain in parts even when all their external stresses are removed.",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld after cooling are tensile, but the transverse stresses are compressive.",
    "Lower residual stresses are verified in welding that uses higher heat input.",
    "There is no way to reduce residual stresses, as they are an intrinsic phenomenon of fusion welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding Residual Stresses:",
    answers: ["Contact regions of bolted joints or ground regions may have residual stresses caused by mechanical effects.",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld after cooling are tensile, but the transverse stresses are compressive.",
    "Lower residual stresses are verified in welding that uses higher heat input.",
    "There is no way to reduce residual stresses, as they are an intrinsic phenomenon of fusion welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"}
];